Welcome to this video about this task about
classes and objects.
We have been given a class diagram which contains
several classes and several inheritances.
We should construct for each of these classes
one object as an instance of exactly that
class.
So, we have to define for each one of those.
Now, I move this task aside here and open a
blank page.
So, now we have to consider each of these
mentioned classes.
And yeah, we start on the top one,
with RentableVehicle.
So, let’s say we have a scooter which we
want to represent.
And this is a RentableVehicle.
We are using the syntax that was introduced
in the lecture as well.
For drawing those objects.
Or representing those objects.
And now first of all, we have the top of
the object which is the name of the object
and which class it belongs to.
So, the text is underlined.
This is important for the object in objects
diagram.
So, this is the syntax that we use here.
And then, we have to define all the parameters
that are required for this class.
And these are given here, in this case
it’s just model.
We can ignore the methods that are given,
we just have to look at the attributes.
And we only have to consider giving the attributes
here.
So, we can say the model is something and
we can define any String here.
So, we can say for instance that our scooter
is the “Commuter deluxe”.
And that’s the model’s name.
Now we are done.
We have a RentableVehicle, and we can continue
with the other classes.
So, we need another one for bicycle.
So, let’s define the bicycle.
This one, let’s just call it b for bicycle.
How we call it depends on ourselves.
So, there’s no name giving the task, so
we can choose the name ourselves.
The bicycle is a rentable vehicle.
That’s why we have to consider both attributes,
those of RentableVehicle and those of Bicycle
because of the inheritance.
That’s why we have to give a model name
here as well.
And we can say this is also some special
bike, let’s say it’s the “Ubari Deluxe”.
And we require further attributes here
for the bicycle.
Because the bicycle has also lights or may
have lights and the size is relevant.
So, let’s say for hasLights we say it’s
true.
So, our bike has lights and the size is
28.
So, just as reminder.
We have to give a size here just as an “Int”.
Because it’s stated so here, we cannot write
something like 28 inches.
So, we have the currency we use.
Actually, this size we use it’s up to ourselves.
We have to use an Int value.
And we could use any measurement here.
So, that’s up to ourselves in this case,
so, just 28 for instance.
Now we continue with the other classes.
We have a MotorizedVehicle.
This one it’s also a RentableVehicle.
But I copied the bicycle here, as a template
just to start with- let’s just say it’s
an “escooter” that we want
to construct here.
And this is a MotorizedVehicle and increase
the size a bit.
We can give any model name here.
So, it doesn’t matter if it’s an actually
existing model or not.
But we can use a model name which is “Pure
Air” here for instance.
We require the model’s name here as well.
Because our MotorizedVehicle is also
a RentableVehicle.
And we also require a license plate.
Please note, that
we do not require the attributes of bicycle
of course, just the attributes where
MotorizedVehicle is.
Because MotorizedVehicles are RentableVehicles.
Because it’s inheriting.
Only from rentable vehicles.
Not from bicycle.
So, that’s why I removed those attributes
here and instead I added the license plate
and for our license plate, we can choose any
value that is String, for instance we could
say our license plate
could look something like this, it contains numbers
and letters.
Maybe this is also a valid license plate but yeah.
The important thing is that we fulfill the requirements
of the types given within the class diagram by
having a “String”.
Okay now, another MotorizedVehicle.
That is the motorcycle.
Let’s define the motorcycle.
And again, we can choose any name we want.
Let’s call it “thebike”.
And we need model name as well.
So, we could choose any model we would like
for instance the “Honda CBX550F” or any
other model you like.
And because it’s a motorized vehicle, it
also has a license plate.
Now because of the task we cannot use the
same license plate as we had before.
Because the task says that we have to choose
a different value.
So, we could say for instance, our
motorcycle has the license plate "DU-AB14".
And the maximum speed needs to be defined
for the motorcycle.
And let’s just say it’s 205.
This is important to consider.
MaxSpeed is of type “Int”.
That’s why we have to choose an Int value.
And it’s up to ourselves again,
which value we want to give and if we think
about it as kilometers per hour or miles per hour,
doesn’t matter in this regard for this task.
Now we define a car, I copied the motorcycle
just as a template.
So, we have a car here.
We require the model, the license plate.
And another value which is new here, which
is the weight.
Again, we have to choose different values.
So, let’s give our car a name.
So, it’s just "acar", that’s the name and
the model.
Let’s say it’s just “AnyCar”.
And the license plate is “E-DU1424”.
These values don’t matter as long as we
have the “Strings”.
And the weight can be defined as any valid
Float value in this case.
So, as what was introduced in the lecture like this
could say the value is like this or we actually state
that this is a float by adding a dot here.
And saying it’s 2500.0 so, that’s clearer,
that we are having floats here.
And as the last class, we are missing the
transporter.
So, this is the last one.
And yeah, we have to have a model again.
Because have a RentableVehicle.
We got to have to have a license plate.
We can choose any different value here, for
instance, let’s say, something like “K-AH1424”
and we can have a weight and height.
Please note.
We have a weight for the transporter as well,
altough we do not inherit from the
MotorizedVehicle.
This is because the transporter has his own
weight defined luckily.
So, we have weight for transporter and car.
But not in general for MotorizedVehicles.
For instance, the motorcycle has no weight
as required parameter here.
So, we required height here.
Let’s say that’s also some random value
here that we choose.
And well, we can choose a model.
Let’s say this is the “T5”.
And we call it "vw".
So, now we have got 6 classes, 6 objects for
our 6 classes.
And important to note is that when we
inherit from another class,
we have to fill all its attributes.
We can completely ignore the methods that
are defined.
And of course, we have to acknowledge also the attributes
that are defined for the class that we are
actually having.
So, for instance, for car we have to give
the weight.
That’s simply what we have to do for this
task.